# **Guy Scott-South**

## Summary

A proven leader, who is a strong advocate for evidence based decision making, with an ability to persuade senior stakeholders with an honest, clear and direct approach. I believe that successful change programmes must begin with a focus on business culture, and I have experience in delivering complex projects, on time, on budget and with consistent implementation.

I have a long track record of leading teams in high pressure environments, delivering results for the customer and business through coaching, development and performance management. I am aware of my own strengths and weaknesses and believe in the power of building a good, rounded team, to deliver greatly more than the sum of its parts. A self-starter with a real passion for learning and development, this has driven me to graduate with an MBA from Cranfield University, allowing me to continue to challenge my thinking and knowledge.

I am focused on delivering long term shareholder value and this along with an appreciation of the value chain informs my approach to business, from managing supplier relationships to implementing projects

#### SKILLS

Data Analytics - Python, DAX, SQL, Cognos, Excel | Statistical Modelling |
Project Management and implementation | Business transformation | P&L management
| Multi Site management | Problem solving | Innovation | Change management |
Continuous improvement | Agile | Lean | Supplier Relationship Management |
Business Strategy

## **EDUCATION**

## **Cranfield University** — MBA

Jan 2016 - Jan 2018,

Electives: Business Law, Strategic HR, Corporate Financial Strategy, Investment & Risk Management, Managing International mergers & acquisitions

Core - The syllabus was highly focused on strategy and organisational change

#### **York College** — A Levels

Sept 2000 - June 2002,

Mathematics B, Physics B, Chemistry B, Biology B, Further Maths (AS) A

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Pizza Hut Restaurants, London - Business Systems Manager

May 2019 - PRESENT

- Responsible for the management and implementation of business software solutions across all functions of the business
- Tendered and managed replacement EPoS project
- Learned Python and SQL to build data integration to existing data warehouse and integration of labour management system into new EPoS
- Delivered a successful ordering and payment solution across the estate in 12 weeks including a full tender for payment processing in order to allow strong trading post Covid
- Learned DAX and built and delivered a training programme for power BI to business teams to automate processes and self-serve data insights

## Pizza Hut Restaurants, London - Insights and Technology Manager

Dec 2017 - May 2019

- Managing and delivering business insights across the wider business through to senior stakeholders and investors in monthly board packs
- Lead the introduction and delivery of handheld ordering devices across 80 keys sites improving operational efficiency and reducing labour costs
- Operations practice audit developing and building a model and tool that allows restaurants to develop action plans to drive financial results and customer experience. Allowing the business to focus its central effort the practices that deliver the greatest results, while providing much clearer performance and risk management across the estate
- Responsible for licencing across the estate, including personal licence training of restaurant managers, renewing personal licences, managing local authorities and the complaints procedure, working with external and internal legal teams
- Providing data insight that is essential to business strategy and investment, by identifying key risks and opportunities through data modelling and statistical analysis
- Leading the operational projects group to ensure consistent on time delivery
- Built and delivered a training programme for the restaurant continuous improvement programme

## Pizza Hut Restaurants, London - Operations Excellence Manager

October 2016 - Dec 2017

- Designing and delivering operational performance improvement programmes
- Source and implement national waste management process improving waste control and achieving zero waste to landfill
- Responsible for maintaining and developing operational standards across
   260 restaurants
- Communicating with regional and area managers to drive consistency of existing and new operational programs

- Analysis of restaurant systems, recommending and encouraging recognised efficiencies
- Development and implementation of performance improvement programmes
- Develop and provide detailed analysis of business KPIs providing information on restaurant performance to senior operations leaders, including spend, customer footfall, capacity utilisation

#### Pizza Hut Restaurants, London - Guest Services Manager

Feb 2015 - Oct 2016

- Responsible for customer service strategy
- Project managed the outsourcing of the customer call centre reducing annual spend by 8%. Improving resolution satisfaction
- Developed guest experience survey to provide actionable insights from customers
- Allowing us to continuously improve business information to develop its restaurants and menu, based on customer feedback
- Periodic reporting for operations board reports and restaurant communications, providing information around outliers and
- Developing and implementing new service routines for the restaurants
- Directly dealing with crisis management from escalated customer complaints

## Pizza Hut Restaurants, London - Operations Communications Manager

Sep 2013 - Feb 2015

- Developing and implementing periodic communications cycle
- Prioritising which projects are delivered by the restaurants throughout the year
- Running the senior operations leaders working group

## Pizza Hut Restaurants, Various Locations - General Manager

Sep 2013 - Feb 2015

- Focussed on turnaround of challenging restaurants by creating and implementing transformation and improvement plans
- Full profit and loss responsibility for a business with circa £1 Million turnover
- Training and development of restaurant team and new managers
- Directly resolving customer complaints
- Continuously improving operations to increase sales, improve experience, and reduce cost
- Stock management and control
- Responsibly of localised health and safety
- Conducting risk assessments and implement procedures to create safe working environments
- Performance management of restaurant team members
- Good working knowledge of team improvement plans and disciplinary procedures

## CONSULTANCY

As part of my MBA I consulted for a Dutch owned stone quarrying and tile manufacturing company in Zambia, building a business plan, including HR, product and marketing strategy, this process also included a full analysis of the company finances and a business valuation. Working with two other consultants, we delivered the completed proposal back to the company within a week.

#### DIGITAL TRANSFORMATION SUMMARY

- Under significant time pressure to get restaurants opened after the Covid lockdown I delivered a completely new digital order and payment solution, integrated into the EPoS, adoption by customers has been extremely high at over 80% and spend is almost 10% higher than traditional ordering. A Tender was completed for an entirely new payment provider, achieving significant transaction cost benefits.
- Initiated and managed the Tender and project delivery of a replacement EPoS system, replacing an aging solution with a modern hybrid cloud solution and standard REST API. Using this API I developed integrations with other systems (scheduling, HR, Accounts) using python to deliver on time and for a fraction of the cost of prebuilt solutions
- Introduced Power BI across functions to allow for rapid self service data analysis, created a training programme to allow functions to automate common data processing tasks, significantly reducing digital waste and increasing productivity
- Introduced Microsoft teams and Power Automate to provide an effective tool for remote working teams to collaborate, worked cross functionally to train others to ensure adoption.
- Designed an operational audit programme for mobile use in restaurants, along with data dashboarding in Power BI to allow restaurant managers to focus on key opportunities specific to their businesses. Using this data I built a statistical model to highlight company wide opportunities with accompanying dashboards to provide actionable insights to the C Suite. This information has been instrumental in the decision making behind the continued turnaround of the brand

#### Interests

- Reading
- Computers and programming
- Sports Squash, Rugby, Hiking
- Cooking